<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ecosystem Science on David LeBauer</title>
    <link>/tags/ecosystem-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ecosystem Science on David LeBauer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 David LeBauer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/ecosystem-science/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>PEcAn Project</title>
      <link>/project/pecan-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pecan-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pecanproject.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Project Homepage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github/pecanproject/pecan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Source Code on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pecan.ncsa.illinois.edu/pecan&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Predictive Ecosystem Analyzer (PEcAn) (see pecanproject.org) is an integrated ecological bioinformatics toolbox (Dietze et al 2013, LeBauer et al, 2013) that consists of: 1) a scientific workflow system to manage the immense amounts of publicly-available environmental data and 2) a Bayesian data assimilation system to synthesize this information within state-of-the-art ecosystems models. This project is motivated by the fact that many of the most pressing questions about global change are not necessarily limited by the need to collect new data as much as by our ability to synthesize existing data. This project seeks to improve this ability by developing a accessibe framework for integrating multiple data sources in a sensible manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PEcAn workflow system allows ecosystem modeling to be more reproducible, automated, and transparent in terms of operations applied to data, and thus ultimately more comprehensible to both peers and the public. It reduces the redundancy of effort among modeling groups, facilitate collaboration, and makes models more accessible the rest of the research community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PEcAn is not itself an ecosystem model, and it can be used to with a variety of different ecosystem models; integrating a model involves writing a wrapper to convert inputs and outputs to and from the standards used by PEcAn. Currently, PEcAn supports over a dozen ecosystem models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
